Guide to the Associations Reference Collection, 1927-ongoing UA.01.11.0080
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Associations Reference collection
1927-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0080
1 Linear Feet
The Associations Reference Collection contains material about organizations other than the university but with which university faculty, staff, and students have been involved. It contains files of clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and printed materials, and was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
approx. 600 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Associations Reference Collection was acquired by the University Archives over time.
Collection Overview
The Associations Reference Collection contains material about organizations other than the university, but with which university faculty, staff, and students have been involved. These organizations, which may be local, regional, or national in scope, include informal unincorporated associations as well as foundations and businesses. The forms of material present include correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed materials, news and magazine clippings, rosters, and forms. Major subjects include the Research Triangle, children's education, Durham's Trinity Park neighborhood, pluralism, and student government. The dates span the years 1927 to 1998 with the bulk being 1964 to 1989.
- Action [an organization of Durham workers], 1971 (Box 1)
- American Association of University Women, Durham, 1964-1975 (Box 1)
- American Tobacco Company, 1964-2000 (Box 1)
- Association of Student Governments, 1965-1969 [2 folders] (Box 1)
- Duke Power / Duke Energy, 1973-1997 (Box 1)
- Duke School for Children, 1983- (Box 1)
- Durham Civic Choral society, 1951-1982 (Box 1)
- Durham Savoyards, Ltd., 1967-1981 (Box 1)
- The Forest at Duke, 1985-1989 (Box 1)
- Forest History Society, circa 1983-1993 (Box 1)
- Independent Scholars' Association - North Carolina Triangle, 1984-1987 (Box 1)
- India Association, Durham, 1974 (Box 1)
- International League for Animal Protection, North Carolina chapter, circa 1974-1977 (Box 1)
- Josiah Charles Trent Memorial Foundation, Inc., circa 1977-1998 (Box 1)
- Junaluska Summer School, 1927 (Box 1)
- Kappa Delta Pi [education honorary], 1952-1977 (Box 1)
- Medical Committee for Human Rights, 1972 (Box 1)
- National Institute of Statistical Sciences - Bylaws, 1990 (Box 2)
- New American Movement, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- Peabody College - proposal, 1979 (Box 2)
- Peace Corps, 1964-1968 (Box 2)
- R. J. Reynolds - The Gilded Leaf, 1979 (Box 2)
- Research Triangle - clippings, circa 1974-1992 (Box 2)
- Research Triangle - memoranda, 1959, 1965 (Box 2)
- Research Triangle - publications, 1959-1989 (Box 2)
- Rhine Research Center, circa 1975- (Box 2)
- Seeman Printery, Inc. - list of publications, undated (Box 2)
- Soul City (N.C.), 1979 (Box 2)
- Société Française (Box 2)
- Tennessee College. Scarritt Graduate Center proposal, 1987 (Box 2)
- Trinity Park Association, 1976-1985 (Box 2)
- Trinity Park Association, clippings, 1976-1998 (Box 2)
- Trinity Park Association, Trinity Park News, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
- Trinity Park Coloring Book, undated (Box 2)
- Trinity Park. National Register of Historic Places, 1979. (Box 2)
- Vocal Arts Ensemble of Durham, 1997 (Box 2)
- Walter Kempner Foundation (Box 2)
- YWCA of Durham - Women of Achievement, 1986-1987 (Box 2)